This video introduces the virtual model IK joint printing function for you.
In this version, we have introduced the virtual model IK joint printing function.
This function allows the virtual model to be imported from outside to be able to use the action and posture provided by Clo.
So let's take a look at the IK joint printing function together.
IK joint printing is currently only supported for FBX files with Google information.
First, we need to import an FBX file to print the IK joint.
Before importing, we need to explain some important things to note before printing IK.
FBX files should not have repeated name joints.
In addition, virtual models must include joints that include shoulders, elbows, wrists, pelvis, knees, and ankles.
T-position is the standard position for reference for IK printing.
IK printing with incorrect positioning may lead to errors.
Therefore,
it is necessary to correctly set the virtual model as T-position.
If the virtual model is not T-position,
it is necessary to manually adjust the joint point of the virtual model in the 3D window to T-position.
In the virtual model information display in the 3D vertical menu bar,
open the virtual model joint point,
then press the joint point of the virtual model,
adjust the virtual model to T-position.
It is necessary to note that
for non-humanoid images or four animal virtual models in the structure,
IK printing may not be correctly applied.
Now,
let us print the IK joint to the virtual model.
In the main menu bar,
find the virtual model editor under the virtual model,
then select the IK joint option card.
Now our virtual model is already T-position.
Next,
press the set T-position in the upper right corner
to identify the adjusted T-position.
If the setting is completed according to the above operations,
the reset position button on the right will be activated.
After adjusting the position during the IK printing process,
the reset position button can help you restore the original position.
Next,
let's print the joint.
There are two main ways to print the joint.
You can manually print each joint,
or you can automatically print the joint by identifying the name of the joint.
First,
let's see how to manually print the joint according to the joint list.
Let's look at the joint list first.
The joint printing is divided into the required and the selected category.
The corresponding joint name is listed under the category.
To ensure that the IK joint printing is accurate,
you must print the desired type of IK joint.
For example,
you must print all the required parts,
but for the selected one,
although it is not a must-set,
if the virtual model has these joints,
you can print them to present more accurate movements and positions.
Now,
let's carefully print the joints of the required project.
First,
when you click on the name of the joint,
you can check the preview on the top
to see which part of the selected joint is located in the virtual model.
You can also directly click on the joint in the preview
to find the corresponding position.
Next,
select the corresponding joint in the 3D window,
or you can first click on the joint in the virtual model,
then click on the project in the option card to print it.
I will print it from the top.
If multiple joints overlap,
you can choose which joint to print.
After printing,
the printing area will be displayed in the preview of the 3D window
and the virtual model editor in the green color.
In the joint list,
there will be a white contrast mark on the left side of the joint,
which indicates that the joint printing is complete.
In addition,
the name of the joint saved for the virtual model
will be displayed next to the printing box on the right.
If you misprinted the joint,
and want to re-select the joint to be printed,
you can select the joint in the joint list,
or the joint in the preview,
then click on another joint to re-print it.
Or you can also select the image in the joint list,
or the joint in the preview,
then press the Delete key on the keyboard to delete it,
and then re-select the correct joint point.
Now,
let's pay attention to the remaining projects.
You can see that when printing the left joint,
the right one is also printed.
This is because the symmetrical printing
is not used in the upper right corner of the virtual model editor.
Therefore,
even if you print one side of the joint,
it will automatically identify and print the other side of the joint.
Please note that
if you want to automatically use symmetrical printing,
the joint name must be left and right,
or letters L and R or small letters L and R,
plus the bottom line is divided left and right.
You can select the joint point,
and then modify the name in the virtual editor.
If you do not open the symmetrical printing,
you need to manually print the left and right joints separately.
Now let's continue to print all the remaining joints below.
Once all the joints of the required project are printed,
the state on the right side of the project will be displayed as complete,
indicating that the IK printing is complete.
Next, let's see how to automatically print the joints.
Before automatically printing the joints,
let's press the reset button at the top,
to reset all the joints printed at the moment.
When you press the auto-print button at the bottom,
all the required joints under the required project will be automatically printed.
You can see that the state is also displayed as complete.
But what you need to pay attention to is that
only when the joint name of the virtual model
is the same as the joint name in the virtual model,
or the virtual model file is from
DeathMiximoCharacterCreator or MetaHuman,
the auto-printing function will work normally.
Next, let's take a look at
how to store the information of the IK joint printing.
The information of the IK joint printing of the virtual model
can be stored as an IKS file.
You can click on the save and open in the upper right corner,
and save the IK data as an IKS file,
or open the stored IKS file.
After completing all the joint printing,
you can directly apply the available posture.
What needs to be explained is that
IKS files only have the same structure,
and are integrated between the virtual models of the same printing method.
You can see that the posture has been correctly applied.
The virtual model file of the IK joint printing can be stored as the virtual model format that can be leaked.
Next time you can use it directly.
By using the new IK joint printing function in the virtual model editor,
you can more easily use various virtual models in the cloud to realize your design.